Guide to the Natural Science Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Original accession
  - DENISON OLMSTED (1791-1859)
    - Correspondence
      - Lathrop, John Hiram with appended note by Henry White, 1843 (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - Maury, Mathew Fontaine, 1837 (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - Moore, Clement C., 1835 (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - Newton, Hubert Anson, 1850 (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - New York Mercantile Library Association, 1834, 1836 (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - Norton, John T., 1831 (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - Olmsted, Lucius D. (last letter is to Julia M. Olmsted), 1851-57, 1861 (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - Parker, John A., 1844 (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - Quick, Charles W., letter of recommendation, 1843 (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - Smith, Hamilton L., 18119, undated (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - United States Naval Lyceum, 1836 (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - Vanuxern, Lardner, 1836 (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - Wightman, J. M., 1844, 1846 (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - Yale College, 1826-33, 1840, 1844-45, 1850 (Box 8, Folder 288)
    - Journal (includes lectures on Chemistry delivered at U. of North Carolina, 1824) [also available on Film HM 188], 1824-1841 (Box 8, Folder 288a)
    - Journal, 1841-1845 (Box 8, Folder 289)
    - Journal, 1845-1850 (Box 8a, Folder 290)
    - Journal, 1856-1859 (Box 9, Folder 291)
    - Family Memoirs -reminiscences of his wife and sons by Olmsted, 1848-1854 (Box 9, Folder 292)
    - Family Journal: entries by various family members, 1834-38, 1841 (Box 9, Folder 293)
    - Universal Memorandum Book, 1843-1854 (Box 10, Folder 294)
    - Articles on Astronomy for various newspapers, 1837, 1842, undated (Box 10, Folder 295)
    - Lectures: Notes for lectures in natural philosophy, astronomy and meteorology, 1843-1857 (Box 10, Folder 296)
    - Lectures: Outlines of Lectures on Meteorology (Box 10, Folder 297)
    - Lecture notes taken by Alfred Hough in Olmsted's natural philosophy course, 1829-1830 (Box 10, Folder 298)
    - "Monody on Dr. Olmsted": a discussion of E. E.A. Poe's satirical epigram, occasioned by Olmsted's work on the fall of meteors in 1833, by Thomas O. Mabbott, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 299)
    - Parting Sentiment at the close of the Astronomical. Lectures, 1857 (Box 10, Folder 300)
    - Report made to the Faculty of Yale College on the Use of Tobacco Among Students, 1846 (Box 10, Folder 301)
    - Valedictory address made to second division of sophmore class, 1817 (Box 10, Folder 302)
    - Scrapbook: Containing account of Meteoric Shower of 1833, etc., 1828-1833 (Box 11, Folder 303)
    - Scrapbook: Miscellaneous matter, 1839-1855 (Box 11, Folder 304)
    - Accounts with Students (3 vols.), 1827-1836 (Box 11, Folder 305)
    - Accounts with Students, 1849-1859 (Box 11, Folder 306)
    - Accounts: personal, 1844-1859 (Box 11, Folder 307)
    - Land records, other financial papers and correspondence Includes an 1848 deed signed by Timothy Dwight, 1816-1859, undated (Box 12, Folder 308)
    - Accounts re: Estate of Denison-Olmsted, 1859 (Box 12, Folder 309)
    - Accounts re: Estate of Denison Olmsted, 1860 (Box 12, Folder 310)
    - Accounts re: Estate of Denison Olmsted, 1861 (Box 12, Folder 311)
    - Accounts re: Estate of Denison Olmsted, 1862 (Box 12, Folder 312)
    - Accounts re: Estate of Denison Olmsted, 1870-1875 (Box 12, Folder 313)
    - Directions for using Olmsted's Stove, 1857 (Box 12, Folder 314)
    - Obituary notices and reminiscence of Olmsted by Benjamin Silliman, Sr., 1859 (Box 12, Folder 315)
    - AD (copy), last will and testament of Denison Olmsted, 1859 (Box 12, Folder 316)
    - AD, account of the estate of Denison Olmsted by his widow, Julia M. Olmsted, executrix., 1869-1872 (Box 12, Folder 316)
      See also: Olmsted's lectures on astronomy before the Senior Class of Yale College, 1838, in Lectures of Nathaniel W. Taylor, taken by S. M. J. Merwin.
    - Power of attorney signed by Cornelia Allyn Olmsted and Denisonn Olmsted, 1844 (Box 12, Folder 317)
    - 7 printed items by or about Denison Olmsted, 1844-1859 (Box 12, Folder 318)
    - Lyman, C. S., "Biographical Sketch of Professor Denison Olmsted," Am. Jour. of Science and Arts, Vol, XXVIII, July, 1859, pp. [109] -118, offprint 8vo., unbound, stitched as issued. (Box 12, Folder 318)
    - Olmsted, Denison, Address on the scientific life and labors of William C. Redfield, Cambridge, Alen and Farnham, Printers, 8vo., unbound, 1858 (Box 12, Folder 318)
    - "On the Electrical Hypotheses of the Aurora Borealis" [ Proceedings of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1850?] pp. 1-10, offprint 8vo., original wrappers. (Box 12, Folder 318)
    - "The Plurality of Worlds," The New Englander, November, 1854, pp. 1-34, offprint 8vo., original wrappers. (Box 12, Folder 318)
    - "Thoughts on the Discovery of Le Verrier's Planet," The New Englander, January, 1847, pp. 1-11, offprint. 8vo., original wrappers. Inscribed on front wrapper: "M. H. Seymour Esq From the Author" (Box 12, Folder 318)
    - Woolsey, Theodore D. "A discourse, commemorative of the life and services of Denison Olmsted." Published by request from the advance sheets of the New Englander for August 1859. New Haven, Printed by Thomas J. Stafford, 1859. 8vo., original wrappers Professor Olmsted's Principal Publications pp.[31]-32 (Box 12, Folder 318)
    - The Yale Literary Magazine, vol. IX, no.9, August, 1844, pp. 385-386 contain Biographical Notice of Professor Olmsted" with an engraved portrait. 8vo., original wrappers (Box 12, Folder 318)
    - Lectures: Notes for lectures in literature, philosophy (moderation) and oratory, 1833, 1837, 1843, 1849., 1833-1849 (Box 13)
    - Manuscript volumes of Denison Olmsted consisting of two journals, 1826 Jan 20 - 1841 Mar 20 and 1850 Nov 9 - 1856 Mar 9, with the earlier journal including "Lectures on Chemistry delivered at the University of North Carolina, 1824 Oct; and The Student's Common-Place Book, 1838., 1826-1856 (Box 14)
  - SAMUEL HAWLEY OLMSTEAD (1838-1893)
    Samuel Hawley Olmstead was born August 9, 1838 in Wilton, Conn. He attended Hopkins Grammar School in New Haven, Conn., of which his father was the Rector.
    After graduating from Yale Medical School in 1861, Dr. Olmstead traveled in Europe, visiting the principal hospitals and studying their methods. He returned home at the outbreak of the Civil War and joined the 170th New York Volunteers, being commissioned an assistant surgeon.
    This collection consists of a description of the weather conditions and the temperature - recorded three times daily, at 7 AM, 1 PM, and 7 PM - from December 12, 1855 to April 13, 1858.
    Note-for additional materials on early studies of meterology see the lecture and book manuscripts by an unidentified author in Box 7, folders 269-283. These materials are described under the heading of "Chemistry" this guide.
    - MS: "Thermometrical and Meteorological Record" (22 leaves), 1855-57 (Box 3, Folder 192)
  - ATTALE RICHE (1851-)
    - ALB to "Mon Cher Confrere", Lyon, France, 5p. discussing geology, 1899 April 26 (Box 4, Folder 215)
  - CORPORAL JOHN C. RICKLI
    - re: The melting of telegraph wire by lightning, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - SIDNEY I. SMlTH
    Sidney Irving Smith, biologist, was born in 1843. He received a Ph.B. from Sheffield Scientific School, Yale, in 1867 and an A.M. from Yale in 1887. He was assistant in zoology from 1867 to 1876, when he was appointed professor of comparative anatomy. Smith was interested in both insects and marine zoology. He was in charge of deep water dredging in Lake Superior for the U.S. Lake Survey in 1871, and for the U. S. Coast Survey about St. George's banks in 1872. He was associated with the U. S. Commission of Fish and Fisheries for many years and became a member of the National Academy of Sciences in 1884. Smith died in 1926.
    The collection consists almost entirely of letters received by Smith, with a few drafts or copies of his replies. Most of the correspondence discusses biological questions, as Smith corresponded with several notable biologists and naturalists of his day, including: Alexander Agassiz, John Sterling Kingsley, Alpheus Spring Packard, Richard Rathbun and Samuel Hubbard Scudder. Smith also received letters from representatives of the U. S. Commission of Fish and Fisheries, the U. S. Lake Survey, and the Geological (and Natural History) Survey of Canada, who often consulted him about the identification of crustacea and other marine animals.
    - Agassiz, Alexander, 1880-82, 1885-86 (Box 4, Folder 195)
    - Agassiz, [L?], 1863 (Box 4, Folder 195)
    - Baird, Spencer F. (U. S. Commission of Fish and Fisheries), 1884-86 (Box 4, Folder 196)
    - [Bate, C.?J, 1882 (Box 4, Folder 197)
    - Benedict, James E., 1885 (Box 4, Folder 197)
    - Campbell, L. [J?], 1886 (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - Carrington, E., 1850 (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - Chicago Academy of Sciences, 1871 (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - Cornstock, C. B. (U. S. Lake Survey), 1871-72 (Box 4, Folder 199)
    - (de Saussure, Dr. Hy?], 1885 (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - Forbes, S. A., 1883 (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - G. H. Merriane Co., 1886 (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - Gibbes Lewis R., 1870 (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - (to) President Gilman, Johns Hopkins, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - Guignard, J. A., 1886 (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - Harger, A. (forwarding letter from Stebbing, Thomas R. R., 1883 (Box 4, Folder 202)
    - [Harst, Geo. J.?], 1884 (Box 4, Folder 202)
    - [Ishokawa, C.?], 1883 (Box 4, Folder 202)
    - Kingsley, John Sterling, 1879-80, 1886; n.y. (Box 4, Folder 203)
    - [Nilman, A. M.1?], 1883-85 (Box 4, Folder 204)
    - (to) Owen, -, 1885 (Box 4, Folder 204)
    - Packard, Alpheus Spring, 1871, 1873-75 (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - R. Friedllander and Sohn, 1885 (Box 4, Folder 206)
    - Rathbun, Richard, 1883, 1885-86, 1888 (Box 4, Folder 207)
    - Ryder, John A. (copy), 1886 (Box 4, Folder 207)
    - Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1864-65, 1860-73, 1876, 1887 (Box 4, Folder 208)
    - [Silvard, S.?], 1883 (Box 4, Folder 209)
    - Sloan, John, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 209)
    - Stebbing, William, 1871-72 (Box 4, Folder 209)
    - Underwood, Lucien Marcus, 1885 (Box 4, Folder 210)
    - U. S. Commission of Fish and Fisheries, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 210)
      See also: Baird, Spencer F., Rathbun, Richard
    - Whiteaves, J. F. (Geological Survey of Canada), 1880-81, 1884-86 (Box 4, Folder 211)
    - Yale College (letter of appointment), 1875 (Box 4, Folder 212)
    - Draft letter of recommendation re: Jas. B. Neal, undated (Box 4, Folder 213)
    - note, undated (Box 4, Folder 214)
    - poem by unidentified author, [1830?] (Box 4, Folder 214)
  - JOHN TORREY (1796-1873)
    John Torrey, a botanist and chemist, received his M.D. degree from the College of Physicians and Surgeons (Columbia), New York City, in 1818. He was one of the founders, in 1817, of the Lyceum of Natural History, which was the forerunner of the New York Academy of Sciences. From 1824 until 1827, Torrey taught chemistry, mineralogy, and geology at the United States Military Academy at West Point. From 1827 to 1855 he was professor of chemistry and natural history at Columnbia University and held, concurrently (1830-1854), the same position at the College of New jersey (later Princeton). In addition, he was appointed state botanist of New York in 1836 and United States assayer for the state of New York in 1853.
    This collection consists entirely of letters written to Torrey and, with the exception of a folder of photo copies of letters from Torrey to the Rev. Lewis D. Schweinitz, all of the letters are addressed to Torrey. Most of the letters are concerned with the subject of botany. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name of the author of the letter.
    - Aiken, W.E., 1832 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Alvord, Benjamin, 1842 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Andrews, T. L., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Antisell, Thomas, no year (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Arnott, George Arnold Walker, 1836 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1859? (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Baltzell, Glover F., 1838 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Barratt, Joseph, 1838 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Barrows, E. S., 1835 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Bartlett, John R., 1850 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Beards lee. Henry Curtiss', 1842 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Beckwith, E. S., 1855 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Bennett, Alva, 1836 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Bigelow, John M., 1850 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Blake, Joseph, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Blake, William Phipps, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Blodgett, John Loomis, 1840 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Boott, William, 1842 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Boykin, W., 1837 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Brace, J. P., 1824 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - William D.Brackenridge, 1850 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Browne, Daniel Jay, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Carey, John, undated (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Carpenter, William, 1842 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Christy, William, 1836 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Clapp, A., 1841 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Comstock, John Lee, 1832, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Cooper, James Graham, 1856 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Cooper, William, 1826, 1853 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Coultas, Harland, 1849 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Decaisne, Joseph, 1841 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Dewey, Chester, 1841 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Eaton, Hezekiah Hurlbert, 1831 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Elliott, Stephen, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Emory, William Hemsley, 1848 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Fremont, John Charles and Jessie Benton, '1845 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Gale, Leonard Dunnell, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Gibbes, Lewis Reeves, 1850 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Greene, Thomas A., 1827 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Greville, Robert Kaye, 1828 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Grinnan, A. G., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Hadley, James, 1846 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Hall, James, 1845 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Halsey, Abraham, 1836 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Hitchcock, Edward, 1836 (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Holmes, Andrew F., 1829 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Holton, Isaac F, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Hooker, William Jackson, 1847 (Box 3, Folder 148a)
    - Hunter, C.L., 1850 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Ives, J.C., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - James, Edwin, 1853 (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - LeConte, John, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Lee. Thomas George, 1841 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Loudon, John Claudius, 1841 (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - Long, Stephen H., 1819 (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Lundgren, I. H., 1852 (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - McMinn, J. M., 1843 (Box 3, Folder 157)
    - Menard, Louis, 1838 (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - Miers, John, 1856 (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - Neisler, H. M., 1852 (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - Newberry, John Strong, 1856, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - Nuttall, Thomas, 1821 (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - Oakes, William, 1834 (Box 3, Folder 163)
    - Ulney, Stephen Thayer, 1845, 1848 (Box 3, Folder 164)
    - Paddock, J. R., 1840 (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - Parry, Charles Christopher, 1850 (Box 3, Folder 166)
    - Percival, Mrs. A. M., 1825 (Box 3, Folder 167)
    - Perrine, Henry, 1833 (Box 3, Folder 168)
    - Pickering, Charles, 1836 (Box 3, Folder 169)
    - Porcher, Francis P., undated (Box 3, Folder 170)
    - Porter, Jacob, 1835 (Box 3, Folder 171)
    - Prestele, Joseph, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 172)
    - Prince, William Robert, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 173)
    - Prior, Richard Chandler Alexander, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 174)
    - Rafinesque, Constantine S., 1829, 1839 (Box 3, Folder 175)
    - Schoolcraft, Henry R., 1854 (Box 3, Folder 176)
    - Schweinitz, Lewis D., 1826, 1832 (Box 3, Folder 177)
    - Scouler, John; Silliman, Benjamin, 1847, 1836 (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - Spillman, William with introductory notes by Buckley, S. B, 1840 (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - Stansbury, Howard, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 180)
    - Thomas, George H., 1850 (Box 3, Folder 181)
    - Torrey, John to Rev. Lewis D. Schweinitz (Photostats), 1822-25, 1830-32, 1835 (Box 3, Folder 182)
    - Treadwell, Oliver Wolcott, 1832 (Box 3, Folder 183)
    - Tully, William, 1846 (Box 3, Folder 184)
    - Vattemare, Alexandre, 1846 (Box 3, Folder 185)
    - Wolle, Jacob, 1840 (Box 3, Folder 186)
    - Whipple, Arniel W., 1855 (Box 3, Folder 187)
    - Woodhouse, Dr. S. W., 1852 (Box 3, Folder 188)
    - Wright, John, 1844 (Box 3, Folder 189)
    - Young, Aaron, Jr., 1847 (Box 3, Folder 190)
    - Zantzinger, William S., 1854 (Box 3, Folder 191)
    - unidentified, 1850 (Box 3, Folder 191a)
  - ARTHUR WILLIAMS WRIGHT (1836-1915)
    Arthur Williams Wright, physicist, was born in Lebanon, Connecticut on September 8, 1836. An outstanding student at Yale, especially in Latin and mathematics, Wright was elected to Phi Beta Kappa. After graduating in 1859, he continued his studies at Yale, taking graduate courses in mathematics, mineralogy, botany and modern languages. In 1861, he was among the first three men in the United States to be awarded the degree of Ph. D. Wright was appointed a tutor in Latin in Yale College in 1863 and a tutor in natural philosophy in 1866. In 1864 and again in 1890, he served as a reviser for new editions of Webster's Dictionary. For one year, beginning in the fall of 1867, Wright also served as an instructor of physics in Sheffield Scientific School. In 1869 he took some time off from teaching to study science in Heidelberg and Berlin prior to assuming his duties in the fall as professor of physics and chemistry at Williams College. In 1872, he returned to Yale as professor of molecular physics and chemistry. Wright personally supervised the construction of the Sloane Physics Laboratory in 1882-1883, which was built according to his specifications. In 1887, he was appointed professor of experimental physics at Yale and in 1906, he became professor emeritus. Wright also served as a consulting specialist to the United States Signal Service from 1881 to 1886. He traveled to LaJunta, Colorado in 1878 as a member of the United States Naval Observatory team sent to study the total solar eclipse. Wright published a number of scientific articles, including ones on the polarization of the solar corona, on his analyses of the gases present in meteorites and on his experiments with X -rays. In 1875 Wright married Susan Forbes Silliman, daughter of Benjamin Silliman, Jr. He died in New Haven on December 19, 1915.
    The Wright papers comprise both professional and family correspondence, articles, scientific materials, Yale College material and asorted memorabilia and biographical and genealogical materials. The letters written from Wright to his wife while he was on scientific expeditions or attending scientific conferences are a valuable source of information on the physicist's activities.
    - General correspondence
      - A-Z, 1881, 1887, 1890, 1892-93, 1895-97, 1899, 1901-02, 1904-06, undated (Box 5, Folder 228)
      - Ames, J. S., 1903 (Box 5, Folder 229)
      - Anthony, William A., 1892, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 229)
      - Brashear, Jno. A., 1890 (Box 5, Folder 229)
      - Buell, Charles E., 1896 (Box 5, Folder 229)
      - Burt, James, [1891]1 (Box 5, Folder 229)
      - Carter, Franklin, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 230)
      - Cox, John, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 230)
      - Ducretet, E., 1901 (Box 5, Folder 230)
      - Gilman, Daniel Cait, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 230)
      - Gooch, F. A., 1897 (Box 5, Folder 230)
      - Hart, Joseph H., 1901 (Box 5, Folder 230)
      - Henry, Mary A., 1892 (Box 5, Folder 230)
      - Hobson, Richmond Pearson, 1901-02 (Box 5, Folder 230)
      - Holden, Warren, 1893 (Box 5, Folder 230)
      - Hubbard, Oliver Payson, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 230)
      - Jacques, W. w., 1899 (Box 5, Folder 231)
      - Jones, Frank J., 1906 (Box 5, Folder 231)
      - Langley, S. P., 1888 (Box 5, Folder 231)
      - Mayer, Alfred M., 1896-97 (Box 5, Folder 231)
      - Martin, T. C., 1896 (Box 5, Folder 231)
      - Mernam (G. and C.) Company, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 231)
      - Metcalfe, James, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 231)
      - National Academy of Sciences, 1881, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 232)
      - Porter, Noah, 1886 (Box 5, Folder 232)
      - Pratt, J. Howard, Jr., 1887, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 232)
      - Quincke, Georg, 1904 (Box 5, Folder 232)
      - Rogers, Joseph A., 1901 (Box 5, Folder 232)
      - Rood, Ogden N., 1896, 1901, undated (Box 5, Folder 232)
      - Rowland, Henry A., 1889 (Box 5, Folder 232)
      - Shearmen, T. S. H., 1890 (Box 5, Folder 233)
      - Sherman, O. T., 1887-38, 1890, 1893, undated (Box 5, Folder 233)
      - Silliman, Benjamin~ Jr., 1874, 1877-78, undated (Box 5, Folder 233)
      - Silliman, Benjamin Douglas, 1889-90 (Box 5, Folder 233)
      - Simonds, W. E., 1893 (Box 5, Folder 233)
      - Sloane, Henry T., 1892 (Box 5, Folder 233)
      - Stevens, W. LeConte, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 233)
      - Thielfall, J.[?] Richard, 1889-90 (Box 5, Folder 234)
      - Webster, Arthur G., 1899 (Box 5, Folder 234)
      - Yale University, 1858, 1884, 1886, 1896-97, 1901, 1903, 1906, undated (Box 5, Folder 234)
      - Unidentified, 1887, 1896, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 234)
    - Family Correspondence
      - Bennett, Susan Silliman (Wright), 1887, 1889, 1893-94, 1897-98, 1909, undated (Box 5, Folder 235)
      - Pugsley, Dorothea Silliman (Wright): letters written by Mary B. Tyler Rogers, Eleanor Root (Silliman), 1898, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 236)
      - Silliman, Benjamin, Jr.; Silliman, Benjamin Douglas (Box 5, Folder system_indicator_8e97324b77cf4088567c9dbc0171f6b5)
        See: General Correspondence
      - Wright, Arthur Williams, 1874-76 (Box 5, Folder 237)
      - Wright, Arthur Williams, 1877-79 (Box 5, Folder 238)
      - Wright, Arthur Williams, 1880-83, 1886-88, 1891) 1895-97, undated (Box 5, Folder 239)
      - Wright Edwin Wright Harriet (Williams), 1881 undated (Box 5, Folder 240)
    - Articles
      - Professor John A. Porter's Translation of the "Kavevala", 1868 (Box 5, Folder 241)
      - "On a Peculiar Form of the Discharge Between the Poles of the Electrical Machine", 1870 (Box 5, Folder 241)
      - "On the Solar Protuberances"; Abstract of a Note Read by Prof. L. Respighi Before the Academia de' Nuovi Lincei (translated by AWW), 1871 (Box 5, Folder 241)
      - "On Certain Forms of the Electrical Discharge in Air", 1871 (Box 5, Folder 241)
      - On a Simple Apparatus for the Production of Ozone with Electricity of High Tension", 1872 (Box 5, Folder 242)
      - "Zollner on the Nature of Comets", 1872 (Box 5, Folder 242)
      - "On the Spectrum of the Zodiacal Lighel", 1874 (Box 5, Folder 242)
      - Oxidation of Alcohol and Ether by Ozone", 1874 (Box 5, Folder 242)
      - "The Zodiacal Light", 1874 (Box 5, Folder 242)
      - "Preliminary Note on an Examination of Gases from the Meteorite of February 12, 1875" (Box 6, Folder 243)
      - "Examination of Gases from the Meteorite of February 12, 1875 " (Box 6, Folder 243)
      - "Spectroscopic Examination of Gases from Meteoric Iron", 1875 (Box 6, Folder 243)
      - "On the Gases Contained in Meteorites", 1876 (Box 6, Folder 243)
      - "The Gases Contained in Meteorites" (second paper), 1876 (Box 6, Folder 243)
      - "On a New Process for the Electrical Deposition of Metals, and for Construeting Metal-Covered Glass Specula", 1877 (Box 6, Folder 243)
      - "On the Production of Transparent Metallic Films by the Electrical Discharge in Exhausted Tubes", 1877 (Box 6, Folder 243)
      - "An Apparatus for the Distillation of Mercury in Vacuo", 1881 (Box 6, Folder 244)
      - "On the Gaseous Substances Contained in the Smoky Quartz of Branchville, Conn. ", 1881 (Box 6, Folder 244)
      - "Polariscopic Observations of Comet, 1881 " (Box 6, Folder 244)
      - "The Polarization of Light from Comet 1881" (Box 6, Folder 244)